export const questions = [
	//Choice 1
	[
		//Group 1
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: 'How many ribs does a normal human being have?',
				options: ['Thirty', 'Forty One', 'Forty Five', 'Twenty Four'],
				answer: 'Twenty Four'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'Tina took dinner at 8:55 p.m. she decided to go to bed 1 hr 20 min later. At what time did she go to bed?',
				options: ['10:15 pm', '10:20 pm', '10:25 pm', '10:30 pm'],
				answer: '10:15 pm'
			}
		],
		//Group 2
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'Which Indian state is bordered by Bhutan, Myanmar and China?',
				options: [
					'Tripura',
					'West Bengal',
					'Arunachal Pradesh',
					'Andhra Pradesh'
				],
				answer: 'Arunachal Pradesh'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'The cube root of 0.000216 is?',
				options: ['0.6', '0.06', '6', '0.006'],
				answer: '0.06'
			}
		],
		//Group 3
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: 'Argentina is named after the Latin name of which metal?',
				options: ['Silver', 'Copper', 'Iron', 'Helium'],
				answer: 'Silver'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'Duty unto Death’ is the motto of which Indian Organization?',
				options: [
					'National Cadet Corps',
					'Reserve Police Force',
					'Border Security Force',
					'Central Bureau of Investigation'
				],
				answer: 'Border Security Force'
			}
		]
	],
	//Choice 2
	[
		//Group 1
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'Which of these languages is not represented on the language panel of the Indian banknotes?',
				options: ['Bhojpuri', 'Urdu', 'Bengali', 'Tamil'],
				answer: 'Bhojpuri'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'The difference between smallest 4 digit number and largest three digit number is ______.',
				options: ['100', '0', '1', '999'],
				answer: '1'
			}
		],
		//Group 2
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'What did Atal Bihari Vajpayee add to Lal Bahadur Shastri’s slogan Jai Jawan, Jai Kisan?',
				options: ['Jai Sultan', 'Jai Hindustan', 'Jai Vigyan', 'Jai Sangram'],
				answer: 'Jai Vigyan'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'The famous sun temple in konark is in which state?',
				options: ['Odisha', 'Assam', 'Tamil Nadu', 'Karnataka'],
				answer: 'Odisha'
			}
		],
		//Group 3
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'A natural spring of hot water, which sometimes rises suddenly into the air from the earth is called _________?',
				options: ['Lagoon', 'Bay', 'Delta', 'Geyser'],
				answer: 'Geyser'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'Which of the following famous monument is the tomb of Muhammad Adil Shah?',
				options: [
					'Gol Gumbaz',
					'Bibi ka Maqbara',
					'Hazira Maqbara',
					'Itmad-ud-Daula'
				],
				answer: 'Gol Gumbaz'
			}
		]
	],
	//Choice 3
	[
		//Group 1
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'Who among the following is known as the ‘Grand Old Man of India’?',
				options: [
					'Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel',
					'Mahatma Gandhi',
					'Lala Lajpat Rai',
					'Dadabhai Naoroji'
				],
				answer: 'Dadabhai Naoroji'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'The heaviest of all the planets also rotates faster than any other planet. Name it.',
				options: ['Venus', 'Jupiter', 'Mercury', 'Neptune'],
				answer: 'Jupiter'
			}
		],
		//Group 2
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'Vasundhara Raje  was the first Chief Minister of _______state.',
				options: ['West Bengal', 'Rajasthan', 'Maharashtra', 'Madhya Pradesh'],
				answer: 'Rajasthan'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'Which instrument is Ustad Allah Rakha associated with?',
				options: ['Sitar', 'Sarangi', 'Tabla', 'Shehnai'],
				answer: 'Tabla'
			}
		],
		//Group 3
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'If oxygen supply is high, the color of the flame would appear _______.',
				options: ['Blue', 'Yellow', 'Red', 'Green'],
				answer: 'Blue'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'Only two Indian Women have received the Bharat Ratna in Music. Lata Mangeshkar and ______.',
				options: [
					'Shreya Ghoshal',
					'Alka Yagnik',
					'M.S. Subbulakshmi',
					'Asha Bhosale'
				],
				answer: 'M.S. Subbulakshmi'
			}
		]
	],
	//Choice 4
	[
		//Group 1
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'From where did Shivaji Maharaj escape by hiding inside a basket?',
				options: ['Agra', 'Lucknow', 'Sinhagad', 'Purandar'],
				answer: 'Agra'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: '18:45 pm is equal to _________.',
				options: [
					'Quarter to 7',
					'Quarter to 6',
					'Quarter past 6',
					'Quarter past 7'
				],
				answer: 'Quarter to 7'
			}
		],
		//Group 2
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: 'Which two states share the same capital – Chandigarh?',
				options: [
					'Jammu Kashmir & Punjab',
					'Rajasthan & Punjab',
					'Haryana & Punjab',
					'Madhya Pradesh & Haryana'
				],
				answer: 'Haryana & Punjab'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'A book containing summarized information on all the branches of knowledge is called ________.',
				options: ['Dictionary', 'Encyclopedia', 'Anthology', 'Directory'],
				answer: 'Encyclopedia'
			}
		],
		//Group 3
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: 'What does L in LASER stand for?',
				options: ['Luminous', 'Lightest', 'Light', 'Lightness'],
				answer: 'Light'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'Marathi Divas is celebrated on ________.',
				options: ['15 February', '22 February', '27 February', '4 March'],
				answer: '27 February'
			}
		]
	],
	//Choice 5
	[
		//Group 1
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: '_____________ is the author of ‘Panchtantra tales’.',
				options: [
					'Khushwant Singh',
					'Vishnu Sharma',
					'Vikram Seth',
					'Vikram Chandra'
				],
				answer: 'Vishnu Sharma'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'Which of the following number is divisible by 3, 6 and 9?',
				options: ['45', '54', '63', ' 81'],
				answer: '54'
			}
		],
		//Group 2
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'On which day do tableau presentations normally take place in front of VIPs in New Delhi?',
				options: [
					'Republic Day',
					'Independence Day',
					'Army Establishment Day',
					'National Maritime Day'
				],
				answer: 'Republic Day'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'Jaundice affects which part of our body?',
				options: ['Lungs', 'Heart', 'Brain', 'Liver'],
				answer: 'Liver'
			}
		],
		//Group 3
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: 'In India, ___________ heads the Department of Space.',
				options: [
					'The President',
					'The Prime Minister',
					'The Defence Minister',
					'The Home Minister'
				],
				answer: 'The Prime Minister'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'Complete the axiom with the correct preposition: Cowards die many times _________ their death.',
				options: ['after', 'before', 'about', 'for'],
				answer: 'before'
			}
		]
	],
	//Choice 6
	[
		//Group 1
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question: 'The simplest form of   1.5 : 2.5    is __________.',
				options: ['6 : 10', '15 : 25', '0.75 : 1.25', '3:5'],
				answer: '3:5'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question:
					'How many words are misspelled in the following sentence:\nThe camal carravan crossed the dessert for a weak before it arrived at the oassis.',
				options: ['3', '2', '4', '5'],
				answer: '5'
			}
		],
		//Group 2
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'The leaves of the ________ tree appear on the flag of the United Nations?',
				options: ['Mulberry', 'Olive', 'Cherry', 'Maple'],
				answer: 'Olive'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'Penicillium is a _________.',
				options: ['Algae', 'Fungus', 'Bacteria', 'Yeast'],
				answer: 'Fungus'
			}
		],
		//Group 3
		[
			{
				id: '1',
				question:
					'Which country has a tri-colour flag with white, blue and red bands?',
				options: ['Russia', 'Canada', 'China', 'Afghanistan'],
				answer: 'Russia'
			},
			{
				id: '2',
				question: 'The square root of (7 + 3√5) (7 - 3√5) is _______.',
				options: ['√5', '2', '4', '2√5'],
				answer: '2'
			}
		]
	]
];
